地球百子  前情回顾
previously on "the 100"...
我觉得我们需要新的开始
i think we deserve a fresh start.
那我可以回到学校吗
does that mean i can go to school?
不行  玛蒂
no, madi.
没人会发现我是夜之血脉
no one's gonna find out i'm a nightblood.
今天我们在此欢迎
today we mark the return
我们深爱的普里亚的归来
of our beloved priya...
黛利拉·贾妮丝·沃克曼  你接受这份荣誉吗
delilah janice workman, do you accept this honor?
我接受
i do.
向大家隆重介绍  普里亚
it is my great honor to present priya.
黛利拉
delilah.
他们的首领是个老头
their leader is some old man.
如果我杀了他
if i kill him...
普莱姆会遵守协议
the primes will honor the deal,
国王会允许你的孩子在圣地长大
and the king will let your child be raised in sanctum.
那交给我吧
then consider it done.
我想我的女儿了  我们可以今晚把她带回来
I miss my daughter. we can get her back tonight.
我会做好准备
i'll prep for insertion.
对不起  克拉克
i'm sorry, clarke.
约瑟芬  你能听到吗
josephine, can you hear me?
- 你很安全  好好呼吸  - 爸爸
- you're safe. breathe. - dad?
很晚了  什么事那么急
it's late. what's the emergency?
萝丝被杀了
rose was killed,
但是杰德把你的家人带回来了
but jade returned with your family.
感谢上帝
thank god.
但首先
first...
告诉我们事实
tell us the truth.
有传言说你和你的家人
there's a rumor that you and your family
在登上地球的飞船之后  要逃走
were running away when you went up to the earth ship.
真荒谬  我们为什么要跑
that's ridiculous. why would we run away?
谁告诉你们的
who told you this?
我
i did.
你们宁愿相信一个陌生人
you would take the word of a stranger
而不是我吗
over me?
怎么了  丽丽
what's the matter, lee-lee?
认不出你最好的朋友了吗
you don't recognize your best friend?
约瑟芬
josephine?
惊喜吧
surprise.
我听说  是你找到了
i heard that you were the one
我不幸坠毁后的身体
to find my last body after my tragic fall.
我听说你在献祭林里找到了艾萨克的尸体
是的
他送圣所的礼物
已经收到了
他不会将自己献祭出去的
请说英语 不要再说听不懂的中文了
english, please.
她杀了我在乎的人
she killed someone i cared for.
我是在保护圣所
i was protecting sanctum...
不让你破坏它
from you.
我也是
so am i.
- 不  - 约瑟芬
- no! - josephine!
你是我坠落前
yours was the last face i saw
见到的最后一个人
before i fell.
现在我们两清了
now we're even.
我知道我们还有很多要商量的
i know we have a lot to discuss,
但现在  我想洗个澡
but right now, i want to have a shower,
脱掉这件丑裙子
get out of this hideous dress.
地 球 百 子
第六季        第五集
翻译： zayn
翻译： RossyGeng
翻译： 见过凌晨四点的洛杉矶
翻译： 风生水起
校对： 噬魂
时间轴/特效：小螺号
统筹：Kate
总监：麦斯
我们跳舞吧
* alors on danse *
* alors on danse... *
声音太大了吗
too loud?
没有
no.
过来
come here.
你昨晚没睡觉  是不是
you didn't sleep, did you?
我回来的第一晚从来不睡
i never do my first night back.
我们得说说凯莉的事
we have to talk about kaylee.
不  我不想
no, we don't.
她的家族害怕你们发现是她杀死了我
her family was afraid that you'd find out she killed me.
所以他们要逃走
that's why they ran.
在黑暗上呆几十年
a couple of decades on ice,
会给他们一个教训
it'll teach them a lesson.
也许不用那么久
it may be considerably less than that.
地球上的人  他们中有多少是宿主
the people from earth ? how many of them are hosts?
我们不清楚
we don't know.
所以你要去查清楚
that's what you're going to find out.
不  不可能
no, no, no. no way.
乔茜
josie.
你有没有礼貌地询问他们
did you ask them nicely?
他们知道加百利在猎杀宿主
they know gabriel targets hosts,
所以他们当然会说没有宿主
so, of course they said they had none.
也许他们说的是真话
maybe they were telling the truth.
我们13个在着陆时都准备了血
all 13 of us had the blood when we landed.
奇怪的是他们更喜欢克拉克的
odds are there are more like clarke.
我在黑暗中的那6年里
in the 6 years that i was on ice,
一个宿主都没有出生
not one single host was born.
一个都没有  如果你当初让我执行育种计划
no one. if you'd just let me run the breeding program,
我们现在就不会面临灭绝危机了
we wouldn't be facing extinction right now.
我不想再提祭祀的事了
we're not talking about oblation again.
那些是我们的人民  活生生的人类
those are our people-- human beings--
不是一群待宰的牛羊
not a herd of cattle to be culled.
没错
that's right.
和平友爱是恩典与荣耀的圣所奉行的信条
peace and love for the grace and glory of sanctum.
恩许是关键
consent is key.
告诉我
tell me something,
■
人人视频APP
美剧、韩剧、日剧
离线高清缓存
支持电视投屏
各大应用商店均可下载
在线看美剧的追剧神器
我这件完美的肉身
did this ferrari i'm wearing consent
同意放弃自己身体了吗
to giving up her body?
我们救你回来是因为我们爱你
we brought you back because we love you.
机不可失
it was now or maybe never.
别让我们后悔这么做
do not make us regret that decision.
这些人很危险  乔茜
these people are dangerous, josie.
如果他们发现我们杀了克拉克
if they find out we killed clarke,
他们会毁掉这个世界
they will burn this world down
就像他们上一个世界那样
just like their last one.
祝福约瑟芬  祝福我王
blessed is josephine. blessed are the primes.
杰德会保护你
jade will be there to protect you.
你可以告诉他们是我们坚持要求的
you can tell them we insisted
因为加百利的孩子们很危险
because of the children of gabriel.
这是你最后的机会了
this is your last chance.
为了弥补失去萝丝的过错
redeem yourself for losing rose.
就当做她是维系我们生命的关键那样  保护好你的主人
protect your prime as if all our lives depend on it
因为确实如此
because they do.
先从她的母亲  艾比开始
start with her mother--abby.
她是个医生
she's a doctor.
她应该知道他们有多少人有这种血脉
she'll know how many of their people have the blood.
他们不知道我们是什么人  杰西
they don't know what we are, josie.
目前为止  我们也不能让他们知道
and for now, we have to keep it that way.
为什么  我们的存在是令人震撼的
why ? what we are is spectacular.
他们理解不了  他们会吓跑的
they won't understand. they'll run.
我们不能让这种事发生
and we can't let that happen,
尤其是在他们会成为我们的
not when they could be the thing
救命稻草的时候
that saves us.
谢谢你帮我检查身体
thank you for examining me.
我知道你今天很难过
i know today is difficult for you.
萝丝本来会成为一个漂亮的贾丝明
rose would have made a beautiful jasmine.
别担心我
don't worry about me.
黛利拉
delilah.
他是从地球来的
he's one of the people from earth,
黛利拉的一个朋友
a friend of delilah's.
我是说普里亚
i mean priya.
现在不是时候  乔丹
it isn't the time, jordan.
我只想把这个给她
i just want to give her this.
你说过雏菊是你最喜欢的花
you said the daisy was your favorite flower.
是的  谢谢你
it is. thank you.
乔丹  昨天她告诉我
jordan, yesterday she told me
她最喜欢的花是海芋
her favorite flowers were the calla lilies.
海芋是很好看
calla lilies are nice.
我是认真的
i'm serious.
圣器里一定发生了什么
something happened in that reliquary.
她变得好像不认识我了
it's like she doesn't even know me.
你冷淡一点  她会主动来找你的
just play it cool. she'll come around.
是的  还有  最好别给
yeah, that and, like, maybe don't get flowers
一夜情对象送花
for a one-night stand.
贝拉米·布莱克  约翰·墨菲
bellamy blake, john murphy,
乔丹·格林
jordan green.
是的  很好
yes, good.
母亲不在这  也许我们应该
mother isn't here. maybe we should--
放松  我在戈多里演过两次乌拉底米尔
relax. i played vladimir in "godot" twice.
演克拉克能有多难
how hard can clarke be?
克拉克
clarke.
玛蒂
madi.
早上好
good morning.
我今天可以去上学吗
can i please go to school today?
为什么不去呢
i don't see why not.
克拉克  我们谈过得
clarke! we talked about this.
很显然  有和我同样血脉的人
apparently, people with blood like mine
都是攻击目标
are a target.
圣所坚持让我带保镖
the primes insisted.
所以玛蒂需要的是
和我一起继续训练
如果她擦破了膝盖怎么办
或者  我不确定  被纸划伤了怎么办
没事吧
everything ok?
是的  没事  其他人呢
yeah. fine. where are the others?
他们在给瑞文和埃默里展示
one of the primes is showing raven and emori
怎么制造一个辐射屏障
how to build a radiation shield.
- 赖克  - 是的
- ryker? - yeah.
我派了厄科和米勒去照看他们
i sent echo and miller to watch their backs.
我妈妈呢
and my mother?
还在图书馆
still in the library.
杰克逊说他看到她头枕着一本书睡着了
jackson said he found her sleeping with her head on a book.
说起书
speaking of books,
我们送你去学校吧
let's get you to school.
- 克拉克  - 放松  她会没事的
- clarke. - chill out. she'll be fine.
放轻松
"chill out"?
- 怎么了  - 没什么
- what? - nothing.
你能开心真是太好了
happiness looks good on you.
我猜你看完医生心情就好了
i take it you had fun with the doctor.
西莲  是的
cillian ? yeah.
只能说他康复还需要些时间
let's just say it'll be a while until he recovers.
给你
here you go.
走吧
let's go.
谢谢你改变想法
thank you for changing your mind.
为什么改变想法了呢
why did you change your mind?
或许我该重新考虑
maybe i should reconsider.
不用  这样挺好
uh, nope. all good here.
我爱你  克拉克
有趣的语言
interesting language.
英文词根
english lexical source.
也许通过混杂语言产生的克里奥尔语
maybe a creole via a pidgin stage.
走吧  我知道母亲在哪
come on. i know where the mother is.
盖亚
gaia...
嘿  冷静
hey, slow down.
玛蒂会没事的
madi will be fine.
没事  他们为夜之血脉给克拉克派了个贴身保镖
fine? they gave clarke a bodyguard for being a nightblood,
她把玛蒂送到学校去了
and she just sends madi to school?
要给你们拿点别的吗
can i get you guys anything else?
女士  能问你点事吗
ma'am, can i ask you something?
叫我BA就好
only if you call me b.a.
昨晚黛利拉怎么了
what happened to delilah last night?
我的女儿和普莱姆家的人融为一体了
our little girl became one with the primes.
你在那啊  怎么了
you were there. what's wrong?
没什么
ah, nothing's wrong.
她就好像不认识我似的
she's acting like she doesn't even know me.
这点不对劲
that's what's wrong.
孩子  我也很想她
oh, child, i miss her, too.
普丽亚回来保佑我们
priya's return blesses us all.
"priya's return blesses us all"?
这话什么意思
what does that even mean?
意思是他们信仰着什么
it means that they believe in something.
应该尊重这种信仰
that faith should be respected.
乔丹  我们在这是客  需要他们的帮助
jordan, we're guests here, and we need their help.
我相信无论你和普丽亚间发生了什么
i'm sure whatever happened between you and priya--
黛利拉
delilah.
是我和黛利拉的事
it happened between me and delilah.
我知道你觉得自己要保护我们大家
i know you think you need to protect us all
因为你无法保护奥克塔维亚
because you couldn't protect octavia,
但我可以保护好自己
but i can take care of myself.
- 我看到他了  - 是吗
- i had him! - did you?
他带我们来这  这样我们就只能步行
he led us here so we'd have to go on foot.
我们是正中他下怀了吗
so we're doing what he wants?
只能这样  否则他就跑了  我不会中他的计
it's that or he gets away, and i don't get his leader,
我的孩子也进不了圣殿
and my baby doesn't get into sanctum.
是的  目前  我们正中他下怀
yes, for now, we're doing what he wants.
这什么东西
what the hell is this stuff?
我叫它熔炉
call it your crucible.
你挣扎的越厉害死得越快
the harder you fight, the faster you die.
混蛋
son of a bitch.
从血中提取了过量的肌酸
the extract pulls excess creatine from the blood.
我们可以用肌酸
we can use that.
艾比  凯恩的肾衰竭了
abby, kane's kidneys have failed.
他需要全面的血液透析
he'll need full hemodialysis for starters.
你知道的
you know that.
不对  我们要对凯恩做的是
wrong. we're gonna use
腹膜透析
kane peritoneal dialysis instead.
他腹部出血了  我们要怎么做
he's got abdominal bleeding. how are you gonna do that?
我不知道
i don't know!
克拉克
clarke.
她两天没睡了
she hasn't slept in two days.
我担心她旧病复发
i'm worried that she might relapse.
我不想吃药
i don't want drugs.
我想救马库斯
i want to save marcus.
有错吗
is there something wrong with that?
你走吧
you go.
我和她聊聊
i'll talk to her.
亡羊补牢  为时不晚
it's better late than never.
圣殿和孟德尔  后代的隐形特质研究
我听到你们说什么了
i heard what you guys were talking about.
这个能帮上忙
this might help.
怎么做
how?
你说他需要透析
you said he needs hemodialysis.
这是关于夜之血脉
this is about nightblood.
没用的
it's worthless.
我读过作者的另一本书
i actually read a book by that same author.
一个优生学计划的宣传
propaganda on a eugenics project--
净化血脉
purifying of the blood line.
为普莱姆的恩典献上祭品
作者约瑟芬·莱特伯恩
你觉得我们在贝卡的实验室做的很糟
and you thought what we did in becca's lab was bad?
那个女人是个怪物
i mean, that woman was a monster.
要么就是个空想家
or a visionary.
能帮我做点笔记吗 谢谢
ok, can you take some notes for me, please?
这片树叶的纤维是
the fiber of this leaf can double
心脏修补网的两倍
as a surgical mesh.
气孔足够大
and the stomata is large enough that the wound
伤口可呼吸
would be able to breathe...
怎么了
what?
你为什么用右手写
why are you writing with your right hand?
克拉克  你没事吧
clarke, are you feeling ok?
给
here.
锤角亚目
the lan hudie rhopalocera.
什么
what?
如果你做不了透析
well, if you can't do dialysis,
这个东西可以代谢尿素和肌酸
this guy metabolizes urea and creatine.
你看  这里写着呢
look, it says so right there.
这太好了  太好了
that's really good! that's good.
去找杰克逊来
go get jackson, please.
这是他们两百年来绘制的地图
200 years, this is all they mapped.
既然安全了为什么要离开  是吗
why leave when you're safe, right?
拜托  墨菲
oh, come on, murphy.
你的冒险精神哪去了
where's your sense of adventure?
我们是先驱者
we're pioneers.
我可不想做先驱者
oh, i don't want to be pioneers.
先驱者们发现了红色区域  结果要么死掉
pioneers find the red zone and wind up dead
要么患上
or get caught
随机发生的日食精神病
in randomly-occurring, psychosis-inducing eclipses.
你真的还想在经历一次吗
you really want to go through that again?
我四处打听过
i've been asking around.
显然  这整个东西都是建在
apparently, this whole thing's built
岩洞系统的顶部
on top of cave systems.
虫子开始兴奋
the bugs start to freak out,
派对在地下进行
the party goes underground.
对  我们要找到自己的岩洞系统
right. so we find our own cave system,
瑞文给我们建了个辐射屏障
raven builds us a radiation shield.
墨菲  我们不能永远呆在这
murphy, we can't stay here forever.
就算能的话
and even if we could,
那剩下的400人怎么办
what about the other 400 of us?
请和我们一起去广场
please join us in the offering grounds
向深爱的萝丝致哀
to say good-bye to our beloved rose...
葬礼在森林
rose is being offered to the woods.
欢迎你们参加
all of you are welcome.
谢谢
thank you.
别想叫我去
don't even think about asking me
参加葬礼
to go to that funeral.
说真的  带乔丹去吧
seriously. take jordan.
能让他舒缓一下被甩的心情
it'll get his mind off of being dumped.
乔丹在哪呢
where is jordan anyway?
我知道他在哪  来吧
i think i know where he is. come on.
嘿  请自便
hey, suit yourself.
但如果他害我们被赶出去了  那你就是先驱者了
but if he gets us kicked out, you're a pioneer.
真的太难过了
just so sad, really.
进去吧  乔茜
ok, just go inside, josie.
那个墨菲有点可爱
that murphy is kind of cute.
有其父必有其子
like father, like son.
开玩笑呢
got to be kidding me.
你不知道
which part of "i hate dead people"
我讨厌死人吗
did you not understand?
安静  墨菲
quiet, murphy.
乔丹  我们知道你在这
jordan, we know you're in here.
你们来干嘛
what the hell are you doing?
做你在普莱姆法亚之前
what you would've done,
会做的事
the you before praimfaya anyway.
信念执着  这才是我喜欢的贝拉米
heart over head. that was my favorite bellamy.
- 你也是吗  - 他们崇拜夜之血脉
- you, too?  - they worship nightbloods.
我想了解一下为何会这样
i'd like to understand why that is.
我想离开
i'd like to leave.
我不可能因为你被甩了
there's no way i'm getting thrown out of the one safe place on this moon
就离开月球上的安全地带
because you got dumped.
这是圣殿的神圣之所
this is sanctum's holiest place.
你们不该来这
you shouldn't be here.
抱歉  我只是  看见你们在台阶上
i'm sorry. i just, uh, i saw you on the steps.
你的保镖也能进来吗
does that mean your bodyguard could, too?
问得好  咱们去外面说吧
good point. let's take this outside.
还不行
not yet.
火焰标志
mark of the flame?
他们都是指挥官
they're all commanders.
所以这个符号才出现在旗子上
that's why the symbol was on the flag.
还都来劲了是吧  咱能走了吗
well, it's all coming together, isn't it? now can we please go?
前排的那几个一定是埃利吉乌斯队的
the ones in the front row must be the original eligius team.
他们有12个人  还带着孩子
there's 12 of them. oh, and they take kids.
家族的爱是强大的动力
familial love is a powerful motivator.
人们愿意做任何事情
people will do anything to ensure
来守护爱人活下去
the survival of the ones they love.
咱们现在确保自身的安全
now let's ensure our survival
赶紧离开这里吧
and get the hell out of here.
芝麻开门
open sesame.
手术室连着地窖
operating room attached to a crypt.
认真的吗
really?
她来过这
she was here.
这是带黛利拉的  我敢肯定
this was delilah's. i'm sure of it.
你还觉得我反应过度吗
still think i'm overreacting?
咱们梳理一下
ok, let's think this through.
天启之后贝卡创造了火焰
becca created the flame after apocalypse one.
很显然在此之前她就把这项技术传给了埃利吉乌斯三号
she obviously provided the tech to eligius three before that.
这就意味着
that means that--
- 他们不是指挥官  - 没错
- they're not commanders. - right.
那他们是谁
so what the hell are they?
咱们去调查一下
let's find out.
蒙蒂也教他如何黑客
monty taught him how to hack, too.
这是我的教育方式
that's my kind of parenting.
不需要黑
no hacking needed.
埃利吉乌斯系统用的都是同一个接入码
the eligius systems all use the same access code.
欧雷卡  试试这个
"eureka." try that.
我们再试一次吧
here we go again.
今天的实验品是布鲁克  地球胚胎47号
today's subject is brooke, earth embryo 47.
黑血
presents with black blood.
地球年龄21岁
21 earth years old,
在孵化器里做了22次
22 doing time in the incubator.
你可以的盖伯瑞尔
you can do this, gabriel.
钻研了25年  全都失败了  这次机会来了
25 years of work, the failures. this is the one.
如果我是对的
if i'm right,
前面所有轮回试验
the reason all previous metempsychosis trials
失败的原因就是
have failed is
■
人人视频APP
美剧、韩剧、日剧
离线高清缓存
支持电视投屏
各大应用商店均可下载
在线看美剧的追剧神器
寄主的神经系统没有发育完全
because the host's neuroanatomy was not developed enough
不足以支撑成熟人类思维的运转
to support the file size of a mature human mind.
盖博瑞尔  快点开始吧
gabriel, let's go.
我负责把她按在试验台上  开始吧
i'll hold her down. do it.
开始什么  他们要做什么
do--do what? what are they doing?
老天啊  给她打镇定剂
for god's sake, give her a sedative!
不行  保持清醒非常重要
we can't. full consciousness is crucial.
你知道的
you know that.
如果这样行得通  我会找个更好的方法
if this works, i'll find a better way,
一个更容易的方法
an easier way, ok?
我发誓
i promise.
延髓背外侧脑桥盖
rostral dorsolateral pontine tegmentum's
现在全部处于休眠状态
now fully dormant.
我们必须等血清到达大脑屏状核
we have to wait for the serum to reach the claustrum.
然后她就休眠了
and dormant.
刚刚他们把那姑娘杀了吗
did they just kill that girl?
难道我们刚目睹了一个人的死亡吗
did we just watch someone die?
心率呼吸正常
heart rate and breathing--normal.
下脑功能依然完整
lower brain function is still intact.
她准备好了
the body's ready.
发生了什么
something's happening.
她正在苏醒
she's waking up.
- 约瑟芬  你听得到吗  - 妈
- josephine, can you hear me? - mom!
圣所
sanctum...
是我的
is mine.
求你了  停下来
please stop!
约瑟芬  嘘
josephine, shh. shh.
放松  没事的
it's ok. it's ok.
约瑟芬  别这样  没关系的
josephine, no. it's ok.
你很安全  你现在很安全
you're safe. you're safe now.
是我啊
it's me.
深呼吸
just breathe.
嘿
hey.
听我说
listen to me.
盖博瑞尔
gabriel?
我们是在现实世界里么
is it real this time?
这是现实世界
this is real.
你脸怎么了
what happened to your face?
我老了
i got old.
我花了25年时间
i've spent the last 25 years
尝试把你带回来
trying to bring you back.
别怕  没关系的
it's ok. it's ok.
这不是他的错  都怪红日
it wasn't his fault. it was the red sun.
日蚀
the eclipse.
我是对的
i was right.
对啊  你是对的
yeah. yes, you were.
结果它不止影响了昆虫
it turns out it affects more than just insects.
我们的记忆也被影响了
our memory drives.
你用逆向工程把我们所有的思想上传上去
you reverse-engineered them to upload our entire minds.
那太有才了
that's brilliant!
你看起来像一老大爷
you look like grandpa.
恭喜啊  圣地亚哥医生
congratulations, dr. santiago.
你战胜了死亡
you've conquered death.
问题的关键是发育完全的大脑
the key is a fully developed brain.
一旦成年宿主的意识丢失了
once the adult host's consciousness is gone,
在驱动里储存的思想就会很容易地上传
the mind stored in the drive uploads with ease.
现在我们还有很多的测试要去做
now, we still have loads of tests to run,
但是到目前为止  约瑟芬她自己的意识
but so far, josie's consciousness, herself,
还是完整的
appears to be whole.
简而言之  接下来会更多
in other words, eureka. more soon.
他们是永恒不朽的
they're immortal.
他们是杀人犯
jordan: they're murderers.
他们杀了黛利拉
they murdered delilah.
如果他们是自愿的话就不是谋杀
it's not murder if they go willingly.
这姑娘看起来像是自愿的吗
jordan: did that girl look willing to you?!
这就是他们让实验简单有效的办法
that's how they made it better, easier,
通过操纵人们的思想  让他们相信
by manipulating people into believing
他们正在为某些伪神
they were sacrificing themselves
牺牲自己
to some false gods.
成为至高无上的一员
"becoming one with the primes,"
就像黛利拉她妈说的那样
like delilah's mother said.
好吧  你有点太尊重他们的信仰了吧
well, so much for respecting their faith.
我的意思是
i mean, no offense.
我们让一群孩子战斗到死来成为你的神
we let a bunch of kids fight to the death to become your god.
墨菲  别说了
murphy, that's enough.
克拉克  你同意这种做法吗
clarke, you're ok with this?
我可没说
well, i didn't say that.
我仅认为他们对我们没威胁
i just don't think they pose a threat to us, that's all.
新氧
医美
专业医美APP
因为严谨  所以专业
新氧
医美
■
双眼皮
○
-
他们对你有威胁了  你是一个夜血
they pose a threat to you. you're a nightblood.
基于我们刚看到的视频
and based on what we just saw,
我认为你是我们唯一能待在这里的原因
i'm thinking that's the only reason they let us stay.
玛蒂  我必须在他们知道她是谁之前
madi. i have to get her
找到她
before they find out what she is.
我跟你一起去
i'll go with you.
把她带到酒馆
bring her back to the tavern
然后我们再决定做什么
so we can decide what to do.
这些骷髅全都叫约瑟芬
these are all her.
嘿  乔丹
hey, jordan...
抱歉刚才质疑你了
i'm sorry i doubted you.
退出系统  我们需要掩盖我们的行踪
log out of the system. we need to cover our tracks.
我不愿意说出口  但是我同意克拉克
i hate to say it, but i agree with clarke.
这不是我们之间的斗争
this isn't our fight.
你依然还想留下
you still want to stay.
我想要生存
i want to live,
明摆着这些人知道如何生存
only these people know how to do that forever,
如何永生
as it turns out.
那也不会太糟糕
that wouldn't suck either.
重新连接隧道外的键盘
reattach the keypad outside the tunnel.
我们就在你后面
we're right behind you.
你想要知道为什么
would you like to know why
你哥把你留在这等死吗
your brother left you out here to die?
你闭嘴
oh, shut up.
在你清醒的时候
you're a hurricane leaving a path of destruction
你就像摧毁一切的飓风
in your wake.
我说了闭嘴
i said, shut up.
所以你痛恨人类  没人在乎
so you hate people. who cares?
把它埋在心里并且克服它
suck up and get over it.
你一点都不了解我
whatever you think you know about me, you don't.
你错了  我曾经就是你
you're wrong. i used to be you.
你肯定清楚你越挣扎
you know that the more you struggle,
你就会陷得越深  而且你束手无策
the deeper you sink, and you can't help it.
至少我在努力尝试
at least i'm trying.
你正在失去你孩子进入圣所的资格
your baby's ticket into sanctum is getting away,
你做什么了
and what are you doing about it?
你什么都没做
nothing.
他不会走远的
he's not getting away.
他正在树上研究我们
he's studying us from the trees.
这就是他告诉我们不要挣扎的原因
that's why he told us not to struggle.
我啥也没看见
i don't see anything.
我丢掉这把枪之后你就看到了
you will as soon as i give up this gun.
在我这么做之前
before i do that, though,
我需要知道
i need to know...
你想死吗
do you want to die?
说出来
just say the word,
我可以让你远离苦海
and i can put you out of our misery.
你觉得你能吓到我吗
you think you can scare me?
开枪啊
do it.
我也经历过
i've been there...
自作孽
self-inflicted.
我知道你也失败了
i see you failed at that, too.
你在浪费我的耐心
you're trying my patience,
所以我只说一遍
so i'm only going to say this once.
只要你还活着  回头是岸
as long as you draw breath, you can turn it around.
现在大家都恨你  又怎样
everybody hates you right now. so what?
当你的肖像和历史上最烂的人一起出现在
talk to me when your face is in the history books
历史书上时记着告诉我
next to the worst people that have ever lived.
藏的很好
like the gray.
把绳子扔给我们  我们就告诉你  你想知道的
toss us the rope, and we'll tell you what you want to know.
告诉我我想知道什么  我再扔给你们绳子
tell me what i want to know, and i'll toss you the rope.
你想知道啥
what do you want to know?
你们有些人的血变异了
some of your people had blood alteration.
这些人有多少  他们也有思维驱动吗
how many? did they have mind drives as well?
别告诉他任何事
don't tell him anything.
一旦你这么做他就会离我们而去
the minute you do, he'll leave us here to die.
你们自便
suit yourself.
但是我能保证的是
but i can guarantee you--ahh--
我能在这耗的时间可比你们长
i can wait longer than you.
咱们这样见面很危险
it's a risk meeting like this.
出什么事了
what's wrong?
他们进入实验室了
they got into the lab.
他们全都知道了
they know everything.
他们知道你的身份了吗
do they know about you?
还不知道  但是无所谓了
not yet, but that doesn't matter now,
因为我的宿主不是唯一的夜血
because my host wasn't the only nightblood.
夜血
nightblood?
他们是这么叫的
that's what they call it.
很好听  是吧
it's pretty cool, huh?
不管怎样  他们有更多的夜血
anyway, they have more.
有多少
how many more?
我不知道  至少一个
i don't know. at least one.
但是肯定会还会有其他的
but there are bound to be others.
如果这没有  那就在他们的船上有
if not down here, then up on their ship.
所以我们别再纠结了
so what do you say we skip the hand wringing
在他们离开这之前  我们把所有
and do what we all know needs to be done
该做的都做了
before they can leave?
因为这是他们马上要做的事
because that is what they're about to do.
那就劝他们别做
so convince them not to.
拉塞尔
russell.
我是不会降低自己身份的
i will not lower myself to their level.
你已经降低了
you already have.
小约
josie.
爸爸  我累了
dad, i'm tired.
我想睡在我自己的床上
i want to sleep in my own bed,
穿着自己的衣服
wear my own clothes.
你会的  在你弄清楚
and you will... right after you find out
他们到底有多少夜之血脉之后
exactly how many of these so-called nightbloods they have.
如果你说得没错  我们就能复活其它人
if you're right, then we can resurrect the others.
我们给你破例的事也就无所谓了
and it won't matter that we jumped the line for you.
你杀死凯莉的事也没关系了
or that you killed kaylee.
是她先杀我的
after she killed me.
行吧  行吧
fine. fine.
我希望你明白这事不会有好结局的
but i hope you know this doesn't end well.
要么他们发现了我的身份
either they find out who i am and kill me
杀掉我后把圣所夷为平地
before burning sanctum to the ground,
要么我们抓住更多他们的人
or we body-snatch more of them
把剩下的人都杀光
and kill the rest
这样他们就没法把圣所夷为平地了
so they don't burn sanctum to the ground.
这就是你在不打破鸡蛋的前提下
this is what happens when you try making an omelet
做煎蛋卷的下场
without breaking any eggs.
克拉克  你明白留下来意味着
clarke, you realize staying says
我们同意他们的所作所为
we're ok with what they're doing.
是啊  另一个选择是什么
yeah, and what's the alternative?
回到太空中
go back to space?
在我们到达一个更不可能维持生命的星球
sleep for another hundred years
之前继续再睡一百年
on our way to a planet even less likely to support life?
我们可以自己修建生存之地
build our own compound.
我们靠自己是撑不下去的
we'll not last out there on our own.
埃默里  厄科和瑞文明天早上就回来了
emori, echo, and raven will be back in the morning.
他们知道该如何建立
they'll know everything we need to build
辐射屏障
a radiation shield.
之后  就只剩下努力了
after that, it's just hard work.
能熬过多少时间呢
over how many lifetimes?
说真的  抵挡多少次日食
no, seriously, how many eclipses?
多少虫群  多少次恐怖袭击
how many swarms? how many terrorist attacks?
我同意约翰的想法
i agree with john.
我也不喜欢他们
i don't like who they are either,
但我们得学会生存下去
but we need them to survive.
他们是谋杀犯
they're murderers,
让人们放弃自己的身体
raising people to give up their bodies,
对人民进行洗脑  让他们相信他们是神
brainwashing them into believing they're gods.
他说得没错
he's right.
这是对贝卡·普拉姆达信仰的曲解
it's a perversion of everything bekka pramheda believed.
他们应该把智慧传递给下一代
the flame was about passing wisdom on to the next line,
而不是全部留给自己
not keeping it all to yourself.
是啊  但是恕我冒昧
yeah, well, no offense,
贝卡也不是神
but becca wasn't a god either.
她只是一个科学家  在实验室里把自己变成了夜之血脉
she was a scientist who made herself a nightblood in the lab
和艾比对克拉克做的事一样
the same way abby did to clarke.
别再说什么自己更胜一筹了
so much for doing better.
嘿  嘿  嘿
hey. hey, hey!
我知道你干了什么
i know what you did.
嘿  嘿  这不是个好主意
hey. hey. bad idea.
别激动
take it easy.
你们没事吧
is everything ok here?
你怎么能接受呢
how can you be ok?
她是你的孩子
she was your child.
我明白  你很思念黛利拉
i know. you miss delilah.
愿人都尊她的名为圣
hallowed be her name.
但她很幸福  乔丹
but she's happy, jordan.
她想让你知道这一点
she wants you to know that.
中头奖了  跟我来
jackpot. follow me.
克拉克
clarke.
有事吗
everything ok?
摆脱她
我需要和你单独谈谈
马上
你先离开一下
give us a minute.
行吧  我们到这里来
fine. we'll go in here.
你刚才想去哪儿
where were you going?
去见我妈妈  怎么了
to see my mother. what's wrong?
这件事我们为什么会有不同的立场
how are we on different sides of this?
我知道他们的生存方式很残酷
i know how they survive seems harsh.
但根据我的所见所闻
but what from what i've seen,
这些人看起来很幸福
these people are happy.
他们的世界就是这样
their world works.
我们摧毁了自己的世界
we destroyed ours.
这和我们无关
this isn't about us.
所以我们可以批判他们  却不能批判自己喽
so we can judge them but not ourselves?
你知道我每天都在怪罪自己
you know i judge myself every day.
我想知道我们和
i want to know the difference
他们之间的区别
between us and them.
我见过他们的脸
被我杀死的那些人的脸
在我的梦里
不是在镜子里
抱歉
i'm sorry.
你能把最后一句话再重复一遍吗
can you repeat that last phrase?
你刚才说的“闪退”似乎是“闪回”的意思
it sounds like "flashpa" means "flashback."
你的意思是在你“梦里”吗
so was it "dream"?
你是谁
who are you?
约瑟芬·莱特伯恩
josephine lightbourne.
很高兴认识你
nice to meet you.
游戏结束了  现在我们谈谈
ok, fun's over. let's talk.
你说句话试试
don't you dare say a word.
没关系  我们可以等到她陷得更深再谈
it's fine. we can wait till she goes under.
我只需要你们中的一个人
i only need one of you.
好了  你听我说
ok, here's the deal.
你死之后  为了活命我会和他谈谈的
i'm gonna talk after you die to save myself.
所以你这是何苦呢
so what are you really accomplishing?
她能像英雄一样死去
she gets a hero's death.
但如果你的沉默是在帮助错误的人
but if your silence helps the wrong side,
你还算英雄吗
are you still a hero?
我数了一下  你杀了12个人
you see, by my count, you've killed 12 of my people,
我们却一个人都没有杀
and we've killed none of yours.
谁是恶人
so who's the villain?
我觉得是你
i'm gonna say you
因为你们绑架了小孩子
since you kidnap little kids.
但你可以证明我错了
but feel free to prove me wrong
然后把绳子扔给我
and toss me that rope.
多少人进行了血液变更
how many people have blood alteration?
看在老天的份上  告诉他
oh, for god's sakes! tell him.
这他妈是什么声音
what the hell is that?!
瞬时风暴
a temporal flare.
赶紧出来逃命
get out and run!
我动不了了  保护好你的孩子
i can't move. save your baby!
我会回来找你的
i'll be back for you.
奥克塔维亚
octavia.
坚持住
hold on!
奥克塔维亚
octavia?
octavia!
你沉下去了
you went under.
我猜你还是想活下去的
i guess you want to live after all.
他逃跑了
he's getting away.
艾比
abby...
你得吃点儿东西
you need to eat something.
克拉克解决了肾脏的问题
clarke solved the kidney problem.
就算你说得对
let's say you're right.
使用船上的血压计
we use the ship's hemosep.
凯恩的血压会下降
kane's blood pressure goes down.
他有梗塞的危险
risk of emboli.
等他恢复正常  我们再次把他打开
once he normalizes, we open him up again,
然后用这些叶子
and we use these leaves
对付我们新发现的出血现象
against the new hemorrhaging we find.
没错  就是这样
yeah, that's right. it's gonna work.
就算手术室里东西都是全的
even if the o.r. was fully stocked,
艾比  这件事将耗费15个小时
abby, we're talking about a 15-hour procedure.
一旦打开沉睡舱
once a pod is open,
马库斯最多有10分钟时间
marcus has 10 minutes, tops.
- 不  你说得不对  - 不  我说的没错
- no, you're wrong.  - no, i'm right.
我说得没错  你不想面对这件事
i'm right, and you don't want to face this
是因为你用这个东西代替了药品
because you've replaced pills with this.
你在干嘛啊
what the hell are you doing?
我想让你看清事实
i am trying to get you to see the truth.
你真的以为我不知道事实吗
you really don't think that i know the truth?
你知道我为什么想救马库斯吗
you want to know why i want to save marcus?
不是因为药片
it's not because of pills.
因为他是个好人
it's because he's good...
是真的好人
and true,
他有活下去的资格
and he deserves to live,
我们没有
and we don't.
你和我  我们站在血女王这一边
you and me--we stood by bloodreina
在黑暗的岁月里
during the dark years,
马库斯是唯一一个
and marcus was the only one
想要阻止她的人
who tried to stop it.
你有试过吗
did you?
我在做好我的工作
i was just doing my job.
每个战争罪犯都是这么说的
said by every war criminal ever.
你要去哪儿
w--where are you going?
你不是说那个妈妈是关键吗
i thought you said the mother is the key.
她就像一场橄榄球赛
oh, she's the whole ball game,
你可以认为是超级碗大赛
the super bowl, if you will.
如果我们想赢的话  我们需要一个更好的教练
and if we're gonna win, i need a better coach.
你想再来一杯吗
would you like another drink?
为什么不呢  谢了
ah, why not? thanks.
给你一分钱  给我讲讲你的故事
penny for your thoughts?
一分钱是什么梗
what's a penny?
是我们那个年代的说法
something from my time.
我来猜猜
let me guess.
贝拉米说服你  我们应该离开天堂
bellamy convinced you that we should leave paradise
到地狱里面碰碰运气
and take our chances in hell?
我为什么要离开我的家呢
why i would leave my home?
没错  好好想想  约翰
that's it. fill in the blanks, john.
这是你第二次这么叫我约翰了
that's the second time you've called me...
好吧  在你吓坏并
ok, before you freak out
大声嚷嚷之前
and raise your voice,
我有个问题要问你
i have a question for you.
你不是克拉克
you're not clarke.
我实话和你说吧
i'm gonna be honest with you.
克拉克死了
clarke's dead.
我父母杀了她  并复活了我
my parents killed her and brought me back.
我的问题是
my question is,
你想不想也长生不老
how would you like to be immortal, too?
洗耳恭听
i'm listening.
■
人人视频APP
美剧、韩剧、日剧
离线高清缓存
支持电视投屏
各大应用商店均可下载
在线看美剧的追剧神器
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177